<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on ARG@ENU</title>
    <link>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on ARG@ENU</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>s.wells@napier.ac.uk</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>s.wells@napier.ac.uk</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://arg.napier.ac.uk/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Posts in Argument Mining</title>
      <link>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/post/2018.04.20_phdadvert/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>s.wells@napier.ac.uk</author>
      <guid>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/post/2018.04.20_phdadvert/</guid>
      <description>Argument Mining, the process of detecting, reconstructing, and extracting argument structure from natural language sources has become a hot topic in Argumentation research in recent years. This is a challenging, multi-disciplinary arena whose questions go to the heart of classical Artificial Intelligence problems related to Knowledge Representation and Natural Language Processing.
Until 31st May 2018, ARG@ENU invites applications for unfunded PhD research posts. Further details and applications can be made via the findaphd advert:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MonkeyPuzzle Beta</title>
      <link>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/post/2018.04.11_monkeypuzzle/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>s.wells@napier.ac.uk</author>
      <guid>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/post/2018.04.11_monkeypuzzle/</guid>
      <description>The latest (beta) version of MonkeyPuzzle, our browser-based argument analysis software, has been deployed: http://arg.napier.ac.uk/monkeypuzzle/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SADFace</title>
      <link>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/post/2018.02.01_sadface/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>s.wells@napier.ac.uk</author>
      <guid>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/post/2018.02.01_sadface/</guid>
      <description>We are pleased to introduce SADFace, our simple argument description format for describing arguments along with associated tools &amp;amp; libraries for creating and using SADFace documents.
 Project page - if you want to learn more, or the Code repository - if you want to start using SADFace immediately  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poster Presentation on Argument Visualisation at Scale</title>
      <link>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/post/2017.06.23_eca_dana/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 14:58:11 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>s.wells@napier.ac.uk</author>
      <guid>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/post/2017.06.23_eca_dana/</guid>
      <description>Dana Khartabil presented a poster at the Second European Conference on Argumentation based upon her Ph.D research. Briefly, we are interested in the tools that are needed to usefully explore increasingly larger datasets of analysed argumentation, whether this comes from hand-analysed datasets like the STCD. This poster forms parrt of the wider Argument Cartography theme.
SHORT ABSTRACT: Argument diagramming has become a standard tool for visualising and exploring the structure of arguments and aiding in their analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poster Presentation on Behaviour Change Arguments</title>
      <link>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/post/2017.06.23_eca_kate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 14:58:11 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>s.wells@napier.ac.uk</author>
      <guid>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/post/2017.06.23_eca_kate/</guid>
      <description>Kate Pangbourne presented a poster at the Second European Conference on Argumentation based upon our joint research into behaviour change campaigns and its associated argumentative practises. Briefly, we are interested in the kinds of arguments that are used in behaviour change campaigns from the Sustainable Transport Domain. This builds on work in to the Sustainable Transport Communication Dataset (STCD) theme.
SHORT ABSTRACT: Poor communication can undermine the preparatory work, conducted over long periods, to construct favourable conditions for a major societal shift in behaviour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ar:Ca:De Games in public</title>
      <link>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/post/2017.04.11_lovelace/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 14:58:11 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>s.wells@napier.ac.uk</author>
      <guid>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/post/2017.04.11_lovelace/</guid>
      <description>With Argument Card Debate (Ar:Ca:De) games we are building online and offline debate games that use &amp;lsquo;Argument Cards&amp;rsquo;, representations of arguments depicted using playing cards. The aim is to support people in engaging with both their own and other people&amp;rsquo;s arguments.
Amantle Craviolatti recently attended the 2017 BCSWomen Lovelace Colloquium to present a poster and talk about her project with other Women in Computing. The poster can be downloaded from our publications page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MonkeyPuzzle Alpha</title>
      <link>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/post/2017.04.04_monkeypuzzle-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>s.wells@napier.ac.uk</author>
      <guid>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/post/2017.04.04_monkeypuzzle-/</guid>
      <description>An Alpha version of MonkeyPuzzle, our browser-based argument analysis software, has been deployed: http://arg.napier.ac.uk/monkeypuzzle/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Argumentation Research @ ENU</title>
      <link>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/post/2017.04.01_argumentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>s.wells@napier.ac.uk</author>
      <guid>http://arg.napier.ac.uk/post/2017.04.01_argumentation/</guid>
      <description>Research into argumentation has become an increasingly hot research topic in AI in recent years. Argumentation Research at Edinburgh Napier University focusses on dialogue and strategy with forays into visualisation, tooling, datasets, and mining.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>